Dibya Darshan Khanal

Kathmandu, Banasthali 44600 Nepal +977-9860463055 | <u>Linkedin</u> dibya.ddk@gmail.com

Adaptable AWS DevOps and SRE Engineer with 4+ years of experience. AWS Certified Solutions Architect and recognized AWS Community Builder. Currently contributing as an SRE Engineer at UBA Solutions, dedicated to solving technological challenges and optimising system reliability and performance.

SKILLS

Cloud Infrastructure: AWS, Azure, Git, Atlassian

Servers: Web, File, Database, Mail, SSH, Virtualization

Automation: Jenkins, Cloudformation, Terraform, Ansible, CodePipeline, GitHub, GitLab

Containerization: ECS, EKS, ECR, DockerHub, Kubernetes, Nexus

Logging and Monitoring: Datadog, Cloudwatch, Cloudtrail, Splunk, Datadog, Site24x7, ELK, Nagios

Scripting: Python, Shell, JavaScript, Groovy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UBA Solutions (A Monotype Partner Company)

Imadol, Lalitpur

Site Reliability Engineer

Dec 2022-Present

- Acquired extensive knowledge and hands-on experience in utilizing advanced monitoring, logging and alerting tools such as Datadog, ELK stack, Grafana, Splunk and other industry-standard solutions.
- Worked extensively with various services within the AWS cloud platform.
- Successfully maintained a 99.95% uptime for an enterprise-level application
- Maintained proactive monitoring and robust incident response mechanisms with 100,000 users per hour with over 150,000 fonts and foundries.

Pagoda Labs (Kwant AI)

Remote

DevOps Engineer

April 2022-Dec 2022

- Worked on legacy applications with multiple framework and third-party services.
- Worked on implementing AWS DevOps using ECS, Fargate, EC2, Elastic Load Balancer, RDS, Auto Scaling, WAF and CloudFront
- Implemented Lambda function to send real-time error logs to Slack Channel.
- Setup and maintained 99.5% uptime of Legacy application along with Database and Linux Servers.

Cloudlava

Kathmandu, Nepal

Software Engineer | Associate Cloud and DevOps

May 2020-March 2022

- Maintained hundreds of websites on WHM and CPanel
- Conducting research and architecting the development of AWS solutions for diverse clients.
- Maintained automation of multiple client websites using Jenkins, CodePipeline and CodeDeploy

- Develop web applications against given designs or specifications using the Django framework and Vue Js
- Contributed to analysis and design of new requirements, fault fixes and team collaboration.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Developed Java CI/CD with Jenkins, SonarQube, Nexus, Docker and Kubernetes
- AWS DevOps for Django app with Codepipeline, ElasticBeanstalk, EC2 and Cloudwatch
- Python Script to automate security assessment and vulnerability scanning of EC2 and ECR images using AWS Inspector V2.
- Jenkins Pipeline setup for multi stage Laravel application
- NodeJs pipeline with AWS SDLC (CodeCommit, CodeDeploy, and CodePipeline)
- Ecommerce website using Python Django, Postgres, VueJs and stripe.

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research area focuses on cloud computing, scalability, system design, security, and AI-driven automation. I aim to enhance scalable system performance and develop secure, robust infrastructures. Additionally, I explore using AI to streamline operations and ensure cloud solutions are resilient against evolving security threats.

Research paper Title: Comparative Security and Compliance Analysis of Serverless Computing Platforms: AWS Lambda, Azure Functions, and Google Cloud Functions (*In-review*)

EDUCATION

PRIME COLLEGE Nayabazar, Kathmandu

Bachelors in Computer Science and Information Technology (BSC.CSIT)

2021

Academic Achievement - 75.17% College Topper - Final Semester (86%)

CERTIFICATIONS

- **AWS Solutions Architect Associate**
- Docker & Kubernetes: The Practical Guide



Community Involvement:

AWS Community Builder: AWS Community Builder Directory

As an AWS Community Builder in the Container category, I've accessed global expert support, engaged in peer learning, and received AWS credits. Enjoying benefits from CloudAcademy, I provide feedback for service enhancement. Plus, direct insights from AWS product teams keep me updated on new features and services.

